I'm gonna go ahead and borrow it, pops.
遠慮なく借りるぜ とっつぁん
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒 西西    校对:西西     时间轴:葛蔓     压制：娜夏
Your Hue is in a critical state.
色相が危険域にあります
Your Crime Coefficient is still fluctuating, but it's possible it could worsen rapidly.
犯罪係数はまだ変動値ですが
さらに急激に悪化する可能性もある
#19: Transparent Shadow
If you don't address your clouded Hue,
これ以上色相を濁らせたまま放置すれば
if worst comes to worst, you could be declared a latent criminal.
最悪の場合…潜在犯認定もあり得ます
Well...
いえね…
I just remembered how my partner
ended up in the same situation long ago.
相棒が昔 今と同じ状況になったことを思い出しまして
What happened after that?
その相棒さんは どうなりましたか
He's not my partner anymore.
相棒ではなくなった
Just one of my subordinates.
今は部下なんですよ
It's ironic.
皮肉なものです
I've been trying my best not to end up
like him, and yet, this is how it all turns out.
ああなるまいと保身に徹してきたというのに
その結果がこれでは…まったく…
What a joke.
I'll set up an intensive therapy program for you immediately.
すぐに集中セラピーをセッティングします
I'll also notify your office—
職場の方にはこちらから連絡…
Please wait.
待ってください
I can't do it yet.
今はまだ困る
Mr. Ginoza...
宜野座さん…
I'll manage to get by, Doc.
先生 やり過ごしてみせますよ
If that's what you want, but I won't be responsible for what happens.
こちらとしては 結果に責任は持てませんよ
My current colleague... is a young woman who was hired this year.
今の同僚…今年採用されたばかりの女の子なんですが
Watching her gives me hope.
彼女を見てると
希望が湧いてくるんですよ
It makes me feel that everything
depends on how you look at the world.
心の持ちようでどうにかなるって…
Professor Saiga...
雑賀先生…
Just get inside.
とにかく入れ
Hm? Hey, hey...
おいおい…
You're even carrying a gun?
銃まで持ってるのか
You can tell?
分かりますか
An old revolver... Am I right?
古臭いリボルバーで　合ってる
It's like you're psychic.
まるで超能力だ
I've told you this many times.
いつも言ってるだろう
It's a simple matter of observation and logical thinking, Kougami.
観察力と論理的思考だよ　狡噛
I think you all know this by now, but Kougami has escaped.
もう全員に連絡が行ったと思うが
狡噛が逃亡した　疑問の余地は一切ない
There's no doubt about it.
You're right.
はい
He'll probably go after Makishima. We will too.
やつは槙島を追うだろう
我々も追い掛ける
If you encounter the fugitive Enforcer, take care of him immediately.
逃亡執行官と遭遇した場合は　速やかに処分しろ
So we're to capture Makishima alive, but shoot Kougami on sight...
槙島は生け捕り
狡噛さんは即時処分
That's right.
そうだ
Why don't we put Kougami aside for now?
狡噛のことを考えるのは今はやめないか
We're bound to run into him if we drive Makishima into a corner.
槙島を追い詰めれば自然に再会できるだろう
I wonder where Makishima is.
槙島はどこにいますかね
We have an ID on his face,
やつの顔は割れているが
but parts of the monitoring system are still undergoing repairs in the wake of the riots.
暴動の余波で　監視システムの何割かはまだ調整中だ
It'll be five days before it's completely operational again.
完全復旧まではあと五日
Until then, we won't be able to rely on facial recognition to help us investigate.
その間　フェイスレコグニションによる捜査は期待できない
Don't you think Makishima will use that time to try and escape?
槙島はその間に行方を晦まし
高飛びの算段をするのでは
No. He's bound to make a move.
いいえ　必ず仕掛けてきます
That man isn't the type to give up just because he's been cornered.
あの男は追い詰められて諦めるようなタイプじゃない
He's compelled to test this world until his dying breath.
最後の最後まで　この世界を試さずにはいられない
He'll confront this society, protected as it
is by the System, with blunt human nature.
システムに守られたこの社会に
剥き出しの人間性を突き付けてくる
That's why...
そのつもりで
Makishima Shougo made that provocative call to Kougami.
狡噛さんにも挑発する電話をかけたんです　槙島聖護は…
A lot's happened.
色々あったと思うけど
Are you okay?
大丈夫
Well... This isn't the time to feel depressed, you know?
まあ…落ち込んでる場合じゃありませんし
I may not be a saint, but I'm all yours if you need to talk.
こんなお姉さんでよかったら　話し相手になるわよ
Come to think of it, I haven't vented at all.
そういえば人に愚痴ってないな
Kougami...
狡噛さんが…
I don't want him to cross the line from latent criminal to murderer.
潜在犯じゃなくて
本物の人殺しになっちゃうなんて
No matter what else happens.
絶対に嫌です
You shouldn't shoulder everything all by yourself.
何もかも…自分で背負い込むっていうのは駄目よ
I'm okay. If you're worried, would you like to check my Hue?
大丈夫ですよ
心配なら色相判定してみます
I was surprised when I checked it myself this morning.
朝自分でチェックしてびっくりしちゃいました
Even after everything that's happened, it's a pale turquoise color.
こんなことになったのに　ペイルターコイズ
Just how cold-hearted must I be?
私　どれだけ薄情なんだろう…
Your heart and your Psycho-Pass are two separate things.
心とサイコパスは別のものよ
Then what does that make a Psycho-Pass?
じゃあ　サイコパスって何なんですか
What is... a person's heart?
心って…
何なんですか
Hm? You didn't sleep?
寝てないのか
I'm having too much trouble predicting what Makishima's next move could be.
次に槙島が何をするのか
その行動予測が　なかなかうまくいかなくて…
So you think that man is going to do something more?
やはり　あの男がもう一度何か仕出かすと
The security network in the
metropolitan area will be fully restored in five days.
後五日で　首都圏のセキュリティーネットワークが完全復旧する
That's what the CID's analyst told me.
刑事課の分析官から仕入れた情報です
To Makishima, that's how long he
has to launch his last fireworks display.
槙島にとって
それが最後の花火を上げるタイムリミットになるでしょう
I made some coffee.
コーヒーが入れてある
It's made from real coffee beans, so it's pretty damn strong.
本物の豆だからめちゃくちゃ濃いぞ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
I looked through the information you brought with you.
お前が持ち出してきた資料には目を通したよ
I can see why you're having trouble.
なるほど　苦戦するわけだ
What's your assessment of him?
雑賀先生の印象は
If there's such a thing as political offenders
in this society managed by the Sibyl System,
シビュラシステム運営下に政治犯というものが存在するとすれば
this man would be one of them.
あの男のことだろうな
Terrorists, anarchists, agitators,
テロリスト　アナキストアジテーター
suicidal revolutionaries with no interest in the people...
民衆に興味のない　自殺願望のある革命家
There's not a decent man among them.
何の道ろくなもんじゃない
By the way, what would you say is the definition of anarchism?
ところでアナキズムの定義とは
It's a denial of government and authority,
支配と権力の否定です
but different from flat-out chaos and disorder.
ただ　混乱と無秩序という意味ではない
That's right.
そうだ
It's about denying an inhuman control
system and building a more human system.
非人間的な支配システムの否定
より人間的なシステムの構築
Makishima is close to being an anarchist,
槙島はアナキストに近いが
but since he delights so much in destruction, he's
somewhat different to the original meaning of the word.
彼ほど破壊を好むとなると
本来の語義からだいぶ離れる
An inhuman control system... Sibyl, then?
非人間的な支配システム…
即ちシビュラですよね
If I were to borrow Max Weber's words,
マックス·ウェーバーの言葉を借りれば
ideal bureaucrats are those who intently
perform their duty without anger or fondness,
理想的な官僚とは「憤怒も不公平もなく　さらに憎しみも激情もなく
without hate or zeal, and without love or personal predilection.
愛も熱狂もなく　ひたすら義務に従う人間のことだ」という
In that sense, the Sibyl System may be
close to the ideal bureaucratic administration.
シビュラシステムは そういう意味では理想の官僚制的行政に近いかもしれない
But that's assuming that all the details we know about Sibyl are true.
ただしそれは…
公表されているシビュラの仕様が全て真実という前提の上での話だ
Makishima told me on the phone that
he came to know the true form of Sibyl.
槙島は電話で俺に「シビュラの正体を知った」と言っていました
He said it wasn't something worth
putting my life on the line to protect.
「お前が命を懸けて守るようなものではない」とも…
Let me quote a little more from Max Weber.
マックス·ウェーバーからもう少し引用しよう
Bureaucratic administration
dominates the people through knowledge.
官僚制的行政は知識によって大衆を支配する
Technical knowledge and practical knowledge.
専門知識と実務知識
Keeping that knowledge increases their superiority.
そして　それを秘密にすることで優越性を高める
Makishima is trying to strip that superiority away.
槙島はその優越性を剥ぎ取ろうとしている
And he almost succeeded.
それはうまくいきかけた
Those riots pushed society right up to a very dangerous line.
例の暴動で この社会はかなりの危険ラインまで脅かされた
And the Ministry of Welfare made
some sort of proposal to Makishima.
そして厚生省から槙島に対して何らかの提案があった
However, he refused that proposal.
だがその提案を拒絶した
I'd like to talk to this Makishima guy
sometime in a session recorded on video or audio.
一度録画か録音付きで
その槙島という男と話してみたいもんだ
For your research?
研究の一環ですか
He doesn't interest me in that way yet.
そういう段階じゃないな
It'd be purely to help your investigation.
純粋に捜査協力のためにだよ
If Makishima was here right now, how
do you think he'd join our conversation?
もしこの席に槙島もいたら
どんなふうに参加してくると思う
He would...
あいつは…
probably respond by quoting Foucault or
Jeremy Bentham the moment you quoted Max Weber.
マックス·ウェーバーを持ち出された次の瞬間には
フーコーやジェレミー·ベンサムの言葉を引用して返すでしょう
Is it really a "system"? Or more like a huge prison?
「システムというよりは 巨大な監獄では」
The Panopticon...
「パノプティコン…」
A facility that allows you to observe
everyone at once. Sibyl is its worst possible form.
「一望監視施設の最悪の発展形」
You can control the maximum number of
prisoners with the minimum number of guards.
「最少の人数で最大の囚人をコントロールする」
He might even quote Gulliver's Travels.
もしかしたら『ガリヴァー旅行記』辺りも引用するかもしれない
He's a cynical man with a distorted sense of humor.
あの男はシニカルで歪んだユーモアの持ち主です
I see... So he lampoons science and
politics that have become too advanced.
なるほど
進み過ぎた科学と政治への風刺として…
He's that kind of man.
そういう男です
Let me ask you a personal question.
踏み込んだ質問をさせてもらう
Do you consider yourself and Makishima to be alike?
君は槙島と自分が似ていると思うか
There are some aspects of him that I can understand.
理解できる点はあります
I don't know anything about his past.
槙島の過去は何も分かっていません
But one thing I'm certain of is that
there was a critical turning point in his life.
ただ一つ確実なのは
やつの人生には重大な転換点があった
The moment he realized that he was idiosyncratic.
自分が特異体質だと気付いた瞬間です
He can control his Psycho-Pass at will.
自分のサイコパスを自在にコントロールできる体質
Some people would probably consider that a privilege.
それを「特権」だと思う人間もいるでしょう
But Makishima didn't.
でも　槙島は違った
What he felt was... probably a sense of alienation.
やつが覚えたのは
おそらく　疎外感です
In this society, if the Sibyl System doesn't acknowledge you,
この社会でシビュラシステムの目に映らないということはある意味
isn't that essentially the same as not being recognized as a human being?
人間としてカウントされないのと同じでは…
A child who wasn't accepted into the group...
仲間に入れてもらえなかった子供
I see. Maybe that's where it all began.
なるほど…
案外そんな気分が槙島の原点なのかもしれないね
That being said, this is all just speculation.
とはいえ全ては推測です
We won't know the truth unless we ask Makishima himself.
本当のところは　本人に聞いてみるまで分からない
But you're not going to ask him, are you?
君は聞くつもりはない
That's right.
はい
When you're done here, come to my study.
片付けが終わったら　書斎に来なさい
I'll show you something interesting.
面白いものを見せよう
Hence, the ones who know Kougami
Shinya's personality and way of thinking
以上のように 狡噛慎也の性格と思考を理解し
and are most suited to predict his
pattern of actions are us at CID Division 1.
行動パターンを予測するに当たって
最も適任なのは我々刑事課一係です
Oh?
I see.
あっ　そう…
So how did it go?
で　どうだった
Our orders remain unchanged.
われわれの任務に変更はない
We, Division 1, will continue to work toward
tracking down Kougami and Makishima Shougo.
狡噛と槙島聖護の追跡は
引き続きわれわれ一係が担当する
That's reckless.
無茶だ…
You and the young lady should both
stop concerning yourselves with those two.
お嬢ちゃんも　それにお前も
もうこれ以上　あの２人に関わり合うべきじゃない
It has to be Division 1!
一係でなきゃ駄目なんだ
If we do it, maybe we can convince
Kougami to surrender before we have to shoot him.
俺たちなら　狡噛を撃つ前に投降を呼び掛けることだって…
Say, Nobuchika...
なあ　伸元
When did you become so soft?
いつからそんなに甘くなった
Even if Ko surrenders, he'll probably
be thrown into a facility and executed.
たとえコウが投降したとしても
あいつは施設に送り込まれて殺処分だろう
As long as we go after Kougami Shinya,
we have no choice but to put our lives on the line.
狡噛慎也を追う以上
俺たちはあいつと命のやりとりをするしかない
That being the case, why don't we leave it to Division 3 and—
だったらいっそ　三係に任せて…
And make it someone else's problem?!
人ごとで済ませって言うのか
I bet you also realized what Kougami
was thinking and just let him be, right?!
どうせあんたも察した上で放っておいたんだろう
I bet you didn't even try to stop him! You just
waved goodbye as he walked out the door, didn't you?!
狡噛が出ていくのを止めもせず
指をくわえて見送ったんだろうが
So that he'd kill Makishima!
あいつに槙島を殺させるために
That's clearly a breach of trust!
れっきとした背任行為いや　犯罪行為だぞ
A criminal act, even!
No matter what excuses you make, you can't deceive the Dominators!
口先でどう言い繕おうと
ドミネーターだけはごまかせない
Do you want me to check your
Crime Coefficient right here and now?!
今この場で犯罪係数を測ってやろうか
Dammit!
くそっ…
くそっ
Everybody leaves me behind...
どいつもこいつも 俺を置き去りにして
and just heads on over to the other side!
勝手に向こう側に行きやがって…
Do you and Kougami want to be heroes that badly?!
あんたも狡噛も そんなに正義の味方になりたいのか
It's not about justice. It's an obsession.
正義じゃない
執念だ
Even though you know there are other, wiser ways to live,
他にもっと賢い生き方があると分かっていても
you feel that if you turn your back on everything
you've worked toward, it's like admitting you lived a lie.
そこに背を向けたら
自分の積み上げてきた全てが嘘になる
I've had moments like that.
そういう瞬間があるんだよ
So this is all because of your pride as Enforcers?
それが 貴様ら執行官の意地だと
It's not because we're Enforcers.
執行官だからじゃない
This is because of our pride as men.
こいつは男の意地ってやつだ
In that case, I have my own pride as well.
だったら俺には俺の意地がある
I'll capture that idiot Kougami with my own
hands at any cost, no matter what anyone says.
狡噛のバカは必ずこの手で止める
誰が何と言おうとだ
He's done for.
あれはもう駄目だな
But under the current circumstances, there's
no one immediately available to use as our pawn.
ただ　今の状況下で即座に手駒にできる人材が…
Huh?
What?
何だと
Is that the final, collective decision by everyone?
それは皆の総括による結論なのか
Yeah... But...
うん…だが…
Well, I can't fully understand with my current capacity.
いや　今この容量では理解しきれない
I'd like to go back there once and check the consensus.
いったんそちらに戻ってコンセンサスを取りたい
What is this?
これは何なんですか
It's an old type anonymous message board.
古いタイプの匿名掲示板だよ
It's operated via several overseas servers.
海外のサーバーを幾つも経由して　運営されている
Overseas servers?
海外のサーバー
If you look in the right places, you can find them.
あるところにはあるんだよ
Anyway, they've managed to stay out of the Sibyl System's attention.
だから　シビュラシステムにも目を付けられていない
The users of this board are former college
professors, journalists, critics, literary scholars...
ここを使ってるのは　元大学教授やジャーナリスト　評論家　文学者
They're the people who the Sibyl System determined were useless.
シビュラシステムによって用済みになったとされた人々
They still comment even now as their frustration builds up,
今でもこう鬱憤がたまると書き込むわけさ
saying things like, "there's nothing good
about Sibyl", or "this part is so problematic".
シビュラなんてろくなもんじゃない
ここがこんなに問題だってね
It might ultimately be fruitless, but it's better
to at least have somewhere to act as an outlet.
不毛かもしれないが
こんな場所がないよりはいいだろう
I started a thread before breakfast.
さっき食事の前に１つスレッドを立てておいた
Ways to cause a complete collapse of the Sibyl System in five days?
Ways to cause a complete collapse of the Sibyl System in five days
This is...
これは…
They responded to my thread as though it were an interesting game.
みんな面白い遊びだと思って乗ってきてくれてね
They all look like stupid jokes to me.
どうにもバカげた冗談ばかりに見えますが…
Then pick whichever joke you think is funniest.
ならお前が一番面白いと思ったジョークを探せ
You and Makishima are alike.
お前と槙島は似た者同士だ
Trust your inspiration.
そのインスピレーションを信じてみるといい
Leak classified information to foreign countries
What's the matter?
If it's not possible to break into the system,
I think a good approach is to start by breaking things that surround it.
To cause a collapse of the Sibyl System,
wouldn't the best way to be to destroy the food autonomy system?
If it's not possible to break into the system,
I think a good approach is to start by breaking things that surround it.
To cause a collapse of the Sibyl System,
wouldn't the best way to be to destroy the food autonomy system?
If it's not possible to break into the system,
I think a good approach is to start by breaking things that surround it.
To cause a collapse of the Sibyl System,
wouldn't the best way to be to destroy the food autonomy system?
どうした
Something caught my eye.
気になる文章が…
What if the Sibyl System collapsed due to a food shortage?
食料不足でシビュラシステムが崩壊…
Hyper-oats...
ハイパーオーツ…
99% of the food currently consumed in this
country is processed food made from hyper-oats.
「今この国の食卓に並ぶのは
９９％がハイパーオーツを原料とする加工食品です」
They're oats that have been genetically
modified for maximum harvest efficiency.
「究極の収穫効率を誇る遺伝子組み換え麦
Currently, we depend solely on this single item.
ただ一品目に依存しています」
An enormous amount of a
"monospecific genus" that eliminates diversity, huh?
「多様性を失った大量の『単一種』か」
I see... If a single fatal defect was found,
it's possible that they could be completely wiped out.
「なるほど 一つ致命的な欠陥が見つかれば
一気に全滅する可能性もある」
That might be Makishima's next target.
これが槙島の次の狙いかも…
Food self-sufficiency, huh?
食料の自給か…
Yes. This might be it.
はい
この手があったかと…
Crops, production systems, genetic modification...
農作物　生産体制　遺伝子組み換え
Do we have information on any of that?
その辺りの資料はありませんか
Leave it to me.
任せろ
Due to the sharp decline in population
and the completion of the Sibyl System,
人口の激減とシビュラシステムの完成により
it became impossible to restrain the
excess density of settlement in urban areas.
人口の都市部への一極集中は歯止めが利かなくなった
But while people can be relocated, land cannot.
だが人は動けても 土地は動かせない
The primary industry of agriculture
was forced to shift to complete automation.
農地における第１次産業は
もはや完全自動化を余儀なくされた
Through mechanized farming by Drones,
ドローンによる作業の機械化
genetically enhanced hyper-oats, and
disease countermeasures using benign viruses,
遺伝子改良されたハイパーオーツと
善玉ウイルスによる疫病対策
we were able to achieve fully automated farming, eliminating agricultural workers from this country.
こうして　完全無人化農耕システムが完成したことにより
この国から農業という職種は消えうせた
Now the Hokuriku area is a vast granary with zero population.
今では北陸全域が人口ゼロの　巨大穀倉生産基地
If there are any problems with crop health management,
もし仮に農作物の健康管理にトラブルが生じたら
hyper-oats, being a monospecific
genus, will be devastated by disease.
単一品種のハイパーオーツは
疫病によって壊滅的な被害を被る
And if the food autonomy system collapses, Japan will have to once again import food.
自給体制が崩壊すれば
日本は再び食料を輸入しなければなりません
The government will once again be forced
to open communications with other countries.
他国に対するコミュニケーションを拒絶していたそれを
急激にあらためなければならない
As food shortages sweep the nation, the entire
Japanese population's Crime Coefficients will rise.
食料不足によって日本国民全体の犯罪係数が上昇
But once they lift the ban on food importation,
they'll have no choice but to relax border security.
食料輸入を解禁すれば
国境警備はどうしても緩めざるを得ない
Refugees will probably start to flow into the country.
難民の流入も始まるでしょう
Once that happens, the very measurement of
Crime Coefficients might become meaningless.
そうなれば　犯罪係数の測定そのものが無意味になるかも…
So what else does he require?
それを実現するためには…
Right now, Makishima needs...
専門家の力が必要です
an expert's help.
今　槙島は…
I knowingly took part in your plan to kill Makishima Shougo.
槙島聖護を殺そうとするお前の計画に
俺は意図的に加担した
And since my actions were deliberate,
the next time I get a surprise check, that'll be it for me.
その自覚がある以上
次に抜き打ち検診を食らったら
それが年貢の納め時だな
I'm really sorry to have put you through this.
本当にご迷惑をお掛けしました
Don't worry about it.
気にするな
This is simply my punishment for shutting
myself up at home and not participating in society.
社会に参加せずに引きこもっていた罰が当たっただけさ
Professor...
先生…
By assisting you, I feel that I've fulfilled my own role. But...
お前に手を貸したことで
俺は俺の役目を果たせたと思ってる
だが…
even so, Kougami...
それでも結局　汚れ仕事は
狡噛…お前一人に押し付けてしまうことになるんだな
I'm dumping all the dirty work on you, after all.
Well, you definitely shouldn't worry about that.
それこそ　気にしないでください
For some reason, I can't even imagine someone else besides me killing him.
なぜだか　俺以外の誰かがあいつを殺すってのが
想像もつかないんですよ
Kougami...
狡噛さん…
Inspector Tsunemori Akane.
「常守朱監視官」
I will now...
「今から…」
tell you the truth behind everything.
「あなたに全ての真実を告げましょう」
There's no way I could love anyone,
Dareka wo aisuru koto nante
Dekiru wake nakutte
But I wish to be loved by someone in turn
The world may not have
Dakedo dareka ni aisaretakute
Ended yesterday after all,
Kawaranai kinou ga zutto tsuzuita to shite mo
But we will not budge
Doko ni mo ike ya shinainda
watashi to kimi
From where we are
Kamisama doko he itte shimatta no nee
God, in favor of which parts have you left us?
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
I receive no reply, I never do
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I walk with you
Anata to iku
Donna tsumi mo
I will share all your sins
Seotte ageru
Together with you
Michi naki michi wo
Aruiteku no
I walk
A trackless path
Anata to futari de
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".